<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yaseen</title>
    <description>A blog maybe or may be some weird sh!t who knows? :-D</description>
    <link>foxt7ot.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="foxt7ot.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 11:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 11:31:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Zen Of Open Source</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Zen of Python has been my inspiration in programming from the early days. I have even found some of its principles priceless in daily life. After nearly delving more than two years with the Open Source world, this is my humble attempt at jotting down the “Do’s and Don’ts” of the Open Source world in the style of The Zen of Python. Consider this to be a tribute to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0020/&quot;&gt;PEP-0020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post consolidates the thoughts of &lt;a href=&quot;http://hintjens.com/blog:43&quot;&gt;Pieter Hintjens&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brunorocha.org/10-rules-of-open-source-projects.html&quot;&gt;Bruno Rocha&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://fossforce.com/2010/05/the-zen-of-open-source/&quot;&gt;Christine Hall&lt;/a&gt; on Open Source, and adds &lt;strong&gt;some of my experience&lt;/strong&gt; to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-zen-of-open-source&quot;&gt;The Zen Of Open Source&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open is better than closed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Explicit license is better than implicit intention.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Public domain is better than copyleft.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Copyleft is better than copyright.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small team is better than working alone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Community is better than a small team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Documentation counts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Special projects aren’t special enough to file patents.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Although practicality beats ideologies,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Patches should never be ignored silently,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unless they break the code.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the face of ambiguity, refuse the temptation to close an issue.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There should be one– and preferably only one –style guide.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Although that way may not be obvious at first unless you’re a bot.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complete project is better than Incomplete one,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Incomplete project is better than none.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is good to use already developed library,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Although it is better to to build library from scratch, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;reinvent the wheel -let’s do more of those&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wanna add something more, comment below.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 07:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>foxt7ot.github.io/zen-of-opensource.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">foxt7ot.github.io/zen-of-opensource.html</guid>
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
        <category>Open Source</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yee-haw.. Now you can comment on posts</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now you can play comments-comments on my posts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; :stuck_out_tongue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have read ample of blogs which shows how to integrate Disqus with Jekyll but found myself unable to succeed as Disqus has updated their embeded code which provides feasibility to integrate Disqus comments in your post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here I am writing a way which is easy af through which you can integrate Disqus in your Jekyll blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create an account on Disqus, &lt;a href=&quot;http://disqus.com/Register&quot;&gt;Register&lt;/a&gt; your forum name.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It will land you to an installation page.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose “Universal Code” from the “Choose your platform option”.&lt;br /&gt;
  It will provide you embed code which you just have to copy and paste it under “_includes” in new file, say “disqus.html”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is the tricky part, as specified on official doc you have to place the code on whichever post you’d like to load Disqus. And we want something like a boolean variable which allows us to load comments on this post and on that post “nope, just don’t do that”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Here comes the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Shopify/liquid/wiki&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/a&gt; for rescue, just assign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;http://{{ site.url }}{{ page.url }}&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;identifier&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;{{ page.disqus_identifier }}&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Head over to “_layouts” edit post.html (I am assuming that you want to add comments in the bottom section of the post and if not, please tweak changes accordingly). Add these line in the end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;comments&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;comments&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;title&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/h1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;include&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/section&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;endif&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Okay enough bullshit,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/bullshit.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;time for some explanation. The value which we had assigned to page.identifier is the value which will uniquely going to identify your posts and will gonna load comments accordingly. We have placed an “If” condition in “post.html” which will work only if we are going to declare a variable named as “comments” and assign a true value to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also don’t forget to add “disqus_identifier” in your posts and define unique value to it. Perhaps you can use GUID for this purpose, &lt;strong&gt;Just my two cents&lt;/strong&gt; :blush:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 08:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>foxt7ot.github.io/disqus-added.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">foxt7ot.github.io/disqus-added.html</guid>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fasting Benefits</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some interesting information about what happens to our Body during fasting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Detoxification Stage 1 (Day 1 To Day 2)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
On the first day of fasting, the blood sugar level drops. The heart slows and blood pressure is reduced. Glycogen is pulled from the muscle causing some weakness. The first wave of cleansing is usually the worst. Headaches, dizziness, nausea, bad breath, and a heavily coated tongue are signs of the first stage of cleansing. Hunger can be the most intense in this period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Detoxification Stage 2 (Day 3 To Day 7)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fats, composed of transformed fatty acids, are broken down to release glycerol from the gliceride molecules and are converted to glucose. The skin may become oily as rancid oils are purged from the body. People with problem-free skin may have a few days of pimples or even a boil. The body embraces the fast and the digestive system is able to take a much-needed rest, focusing all of its energies on cleansing and healing. White blood cell and immune system activity increases. You may feel pain in your lungs. The cleansing organs and the lungs are in the process of being repaired. The breath is still foul and the tongue coated. Within the intestine, the colon is being repaired and impacted feces on the intestinal wall start to loosen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Detoxification Stage 3 (Day 8 to Day 15)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You will experience enhanced energy, clear-mindedness and feel better. On the downside, old injuries may become irritated and painful. This is a result of the body’s increased ability to heal during fasting. If you had broken your arm 10 years before, there is scar tissue around the break. At the time of the break, the body’s ability to heal was directly related to lifestyle. If you lived on a junk-food diet, the body’s natural healing ability was compromised. During fasting, the body’s healing process is at optimum efficiency. As the body scours for dead or damaged tissue, the lymphocytes enter the older, damaged tissue secreting substances to dissolve the damaged cells. These substances irritate the nerves in the surrounding region and cause a reoccurrence of aches from previously injured areas that may have disappeared years earlier. The pain is good as the body is completing the healing process. The muscles may become tight and sore due to toxin irritation. The legs can be the worst affected, as toxins accumulate in the legs. Cankers are common in this stage due to the excessive bacteria in the mouth. Daily gargling with salt and water will prevent or heal cankers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Detoxification Stage 4 (Day 16 to Day 30)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The body is completely adapted to the fasting process. There is more energy and clarity of mind. Cleansing periods can be short with many days of feeling good in between. There are days when the tongue is pink and the breath is fresh. The healing work of the organs is being completed. After the detoxification mechanisms have removed the causative agent or render it harmless, the body works at maximum capacity in tissue proliferation to replace damaged tissue. After day 20, the mind is affected. Heightened clarity and emotional balance are felt at this time. Memory and concentration improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Happy Fasting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Above excerpts are copied form the researcher, Mr. Tom McGregor, author of Eating in Freedom&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 08:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>foxt7ot.github.io/fasting-benefits.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">foxt7ot.github.io/fasting-benefits.html</guid>
        
        <category>spiritual</category>
        
        <category>religious</category>
        
        <category>science</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ramadhan (A programming towards Patience)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the current and next few weeks, you may come into work and find your co-worker taking a power nap at 9:30am. At break time, you’ll notice he\she is missing in the discussion about Harry Potter over at the water cooler. At the staff meeting, you will be shocked when he\she is offered coffee and cookies and refuses ! By lunch time, your concern about his\her missing at the water cooler compels you to investigate the situation.&lt;br /&gt;
Then you remember what he\she had mentioned last week over a delicious lunch. Flooded with relief, you go up to his\her desk, and proclaim with much gusto, “Ramadan Mubarak (Moo-baa-rak)!” Ramadan’s Blessings to you!&lt;br /&gt;
The month of Ramadan is a happy occasion; it is the month that the Muslim holy book, &lt;strong&gt;The Quran&lt;/strong&gt;, was revealed to our Prophet Muhammad(Peace be upon him). Muslims are called by their religion to celebrate the month by coming together in worship, fasting each day for thirty days from dawn until sunset. While this may seem like a tremendous feat, consider this:&lt;br /&gt;
Fasting while working is an even greater endeavor. Make it a little easier on your Muslim colleague by following a couple of simple rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Greeting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The next time you find yourself in line for the copier with your Muslim colleague, feel free to wish him or her “Ramadan Mubarak” or “Ramadan Kareem” or simply “Happy Ramadan.” We absolutely love it when people acknowledge Ramadan and are happy about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Positive Reinforcement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Keep in mind that we’re fasting voluntarily and, actually, pretty joyously (despite the tired, sad look on our face). We’re not forced to fast. In fact, there are immense amount of &lt;a href=&quot;/fasting-benefits.html&quot;&gt;benefits of fasting&lt;/a&gt; and we wait for this month the whole year, so you don’t have to feel sorry for us. We are not trying to be rescued (other than by that ticking clock taking us closer to sunset!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Lunch Meeting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Most of us understand that life goes on, and so do lunch meetings, and if we are participating in them while fasting, don’t worry about eating in front of us. This is just part of the test. We appreciate your acknowledging our fast, but don’t feel the need to discuss it every time you show up in our line of sight holding food.&lt;br /&gt;
Just try not to eat smelly foods. . . and please ignore our stomach when it growls at your sandwich. :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;No Water&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It’s true — we can’t drink water either. Again, this is part of the Ramadan test and our exercise of spiritual discipline. This is probably why you may not find your friend at the water cooler. Try switching the break time conversation to another location in the office. You should probably also let them skip their turn for the coffee run this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Iftar Dinner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Consider holding a Ramadan Iftar dinner. Iftar is the Arabic word for the meal served at sunset when we break the fast (it’s literally our ‘breakfast’). This will be a nice gesture for Muslim coworkers and will give others the opportunity to learn about and partake in Ramadan festivities. Although there is no specific type of meal designated for iftars, it is is tradition to break the fast with a sweet and refreshing date before moving to a full-on dinner.&lt;br /&gt;
Fasting is not an excuse, Although energy levels might be low, the point of fasting is not to slack off from our other duties and responsibilities. We believe that we are rewarded for continuing to work and produce during our fasts. Fasting is not a reason to push meetings, clear schedules, or take a lighter load on projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said – we don’t mind if you help work in a nap time for us! :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 08:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>foxt7ot.github.io/welcome-ramadhan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">foxt7ot.github.io/welcome-ramadhan.html</guid>
        
        <category>spiritual</category>
        
        <category>religious</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This world is so Meta, Even this post is...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;And on this nice and shiny day of summer I took decision to move ahead of old blog powered by Wordpress to this new one powered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gh-pages&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; pages with an essence of &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. There is very slight chances that I’ll repost my old posts in this blog as there are many reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First and foremost, I am too lazy to do so.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BlackBerry 10 is long gone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Firefox OS has been shut down. So, as a result there is no use to build custom &lt;strong&gt;gaia&lt;/strong&gt;.(If still you are interested ping me on IRC [sudoname: foxt7ot])&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what exactly you can find in this blog? Mumble-Jumbled posts, yeah that’s right. Post on technologies, religions, Movies and what not.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 08:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>foxt7ot.github.io/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">foxt7ot.github.io/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        <category>firstpost</category>
        
        <category>newSunshine</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
