<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <title>Tag: religious</title>
 <link href="foxt7ot.github.io/tag/religious.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="foxt7ot.github.io/tag/religious.html"/>
 <updated>2016-07-25T11:52:54+00:00</updated>
 <id>foxt7ot.github.io/tag/religious.html</id>
 <author>
   <name>Yaseen</name>
 </author>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fasting Benefits</title>
   <link href="foxt7ot.github.io/fasting-benefits.html"/>
   <updated>2016-06-22T08:37:36+00:00</updated>
   <id>foxt7ot.github.io/fasting-benefits.html</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some interesting information about what happens to our Body during fasting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Detoxification Stage 1 (Day 1 To Day 2)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
On the first day of fasting, the blood sugar level drops. The heart slows and blood pressure is reduced. Glycogen is pulled from the muscle causing some weakness. The first wave of cleansing is usually the worst. Headaches, dizziness, nausea, bad breath, and a heavily coated tongue are signs of the first stage of cleansing. Hunger can be the most intense in this period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Detoxification Stage 2 (Day 3 To Day 7)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fats, composed of transformed fatty acids, are broken down to release glycerol from the gliceride molecules and are converted to glucose. The skin may become oily as rancid oils are purged from the body. People with problem-free skin may have a few days of pimples or even a boil. The body embraces the fast and the digestive system is able to take a much-needed rest, focusing all of its energies on cleansing and healing. White blood cell and immune system activity increases. You may feel pain in your lungs. The cleansing organs and the lungs are in the process of being repaired. The breath is still foul and the tongue coated. Within the intestine, the colon is being repaired and impacted feces on the intestinal wall start to loosen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Detoxification Stage 3 (Day 8 to Day 15)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You will experience enhanced energy, clear-mindedness and feel better. On the downside, old injuries may become irritated and painful. This is a result of the body’s increased ability to heal during fasting. If you had broken your arm 10 years before, there is scar tissue around the break. At the time of the break, the body’s ability to heal was directly related to lifestyle. If you lived on a junk-food diet, the body’s natural healing ability was compromised. During fasting, the body’s healing process is at optimum efficiency. As the body scours for dead or damaged tissue, the lymphocytes enter the older, damaged tissue secreting substances to dissolve the damaged cells. These substances irritate the nerves in the surrounding region and cause a reoccurrence of aches from previously injured areas that may have disappeared years earlier. The pain is good as the body is completing the healing process. The muscles may become tight and sore due to toxin irritation. The legs can be the worst affected, as toxins accumulate in the legs. Cankers are common in this stage due to the excessive bacteria in the mouth. Daily gargling with salt and water will prevent or heal cankers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Detoxification Stage 4 (Day 16 to Day 30)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The body is completely adapted to the fasting process. There is more energy and clarity of mind. Cleansing periods can be short with many days of feeling good in between. There are days when the tongue is pink and the breath is fresh. The healing work of the organs is being completed. After the detoxification mechanisms have removed the causative agent or render it harmless, the body works at maximum capacity in tissue proliferation to replace damaged tissue. After day 20, the mind is affected. Heightened clarity and emotional balance are felt at this time. Memory and concentration improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Happy Fasting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Above excerpts are copied form the researcher, Mr. Tom McGregor, author of Eating in Freedom&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ramadhan (A programming towards Patience)</title>
   <link href="foxt7ot.github.io/welcome-ramadhan.html"/>
   <updated>2016-06-02T08:37:36+00:00</updated>
   <id>foxt7ot.github.io/welcome-ramadhan.html</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the current and next few weeks, you may come into work and find your co-worker taking a power nap at 9:30am. At break time, you’ll notice he\she is missing in the discussion about Harry Potter over at the water cooler. At the staff meeting, you will be shocked when he\she is offered coffee and cookies and refuses ! By lunch time, your concern about his\her missing at the water cooler compels you to investigate the situation.&lt;br /&gt;
Then you remember what he\she had mentioned last week over a delicious lunch. Flooded with relief, you go up to his\her desk, and proclaim with much gusto, “Ramadan Mubarak (Moo-baa-rak)!” Ramadan’s Blessings to you!&lt;br /&gt;
The month of Ramadan is a happy occasion; it is the month that the Muslim holy book, &lt;strong&gt;The Quran&lt;/strong&gt;, was revealed to our Prophet Muhammad(Peace be upon him). Muslims are called by their religion to celebrate the month by coming together in worship, fasting each day for thirty days from dawn until sunset. While this may seem like a tremendous feat, consider this:&lt;br /&gt;
Fasting while working is an even greater endeavor. Make it a little easier on your Muslim colleague by following a couple of simple rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Greeting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The next time you find yourself in line for the copier with your Muslim colleague, feel free to wish him or her “Ramadan Mubarak” or “Ramadan Kareem” or simply “Happy Ramadan.” We absolutely love it when people acknowledge Ramadan and are happy about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Positive Reinforcement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Keep in mind that we’re fasting voluntarily and, actually, pretty joyously (despite the tired, sad look on our face). We’re not forced to fast. In fact, there are immense amount of &lt;a href=&quot;/fasting-benefits.html&quot;&gt;benefits of fasting&lt;/a&gt; and we wait for this month the whole year, so you don’t have to feel sorry for us. We are not trying to be rescued (other than by that ticking clock taking us closer to sunset!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Lunch Meeting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Most of us understand that life goes on, and so do lunch meetings, and if we are participating in them while fasting, don’t worry about eating in front of us. This is just part of the test. We appreciate your acknowledging our fast, but don’t feel the need to discuss it every time you show up in our line of sight holding food.&lt;br /&gt;
Just try not to eat smelly foods. . . and please ignore our stomach when it growls at your sandwich. :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;No Water&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It’s true — we can’t drink water either. Again, this is part of the Ramadan test and our exercise of spiritual discipline. This is probably why you may not find your friend at the water cooler. Try switching the break time conversation to another location in the office. You should probably also let them skip their turn for the coffee run this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Iftar Dinner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Consider holding a Ramadan Iftar dinner. Iftar is the Arabic word for the meal served at sunset when we break the fast (it’s literally our ‘breakfast’). This will be a nice gesture for Muslim coworkers and will give others the opportunity to learn about and partake in Ramadan festivities. Although there is no specific type of meal designated for iftars, it is is tradition to break the fast with a sweet and refreshing date before moving to a full-on dinner.&lt;br /&gt;
Fasting is not an excuse, Although energy levels might be low, the point of fasting is not to slack off from our other duties and responsibilities. We believe that we are rewarded for continuing to work and produce during our fasts. Fasting is not a reason to push meetings, clear schedules, or take a lighter load on projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said – we don’t mind if you help work in a nap time for us! :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
</feed>
